Guide to the Howard Zinn Papers TAM.542
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series II: Correspondence, 1962-2010
  In addition to general correspondence, the series also contains two specific groups of letters. The first, reflecting Zinn's interest in justice and the rights of the incarcerated, consists of correspondence with prisoners; some are well-known, such as Kathy Boudin and Mumia Abu-Jamal. The second group of letters involves students, many at the secondary school level. A number of teachers either introduced Zinn writings in their class or invited him to visit and speak to the students. In both cases, the students were asked to write to Zinn with their reactions, questions or criticisms.
  - Correspondence (includes several letters from Irving Howe and from Dick Schaap), 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1965-Jun 1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Wilfrid Sheed), Jul 1965-Dec 1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Herbert Aptheker), Jan 1966-Jun 1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (includes letters from Eqbal Ahmad, from David Riesman, and from C.Vann Woodward), Jul 1966-Dec 1966 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence (includes letters from Otto Nathan and from Noam Chomsky), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Richard Nixon), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence (re: Boston Globe columns, 1975), Jan 1975-Mar 1975 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence (re: Boston Globe columns, 1975), Apr 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (re: Boston Globe columns, 1976) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Eqbal Ahmad), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (includes letters from Marilyn French and from Victor Navasky), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Noam Chomsky), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Ron Kovic), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1998-Jun 1998 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence (includes post card from Oliver Stone), Jul 1998-Dec 1998 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence (includes letters from Howard Fast, from Oliver Stone and from Tim Robbins; also, greeting card from Ron Kovic), 1999 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Ralph Nader), 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (includes correspondence and book from Patch Adams), Jan 2001-May 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Jun 2001-Sep 2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Oct 2001-Dec 2001 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jan 2002-Aug 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Sep 2002-Dec 2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Bill Moyers), Jan 2003-Jun 2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Lori Berenson), Jul 2003-Dec 2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (includes letters from Andre Gregory and from Viggo Mortensen), Jan 2004-May 2004 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Elizabeth Edwards), Jun 2004-Dec 2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Oliver Stone, and copy of Zinn response), Jan 2005-Feb 2005 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Mar 2005-Apr 2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, May 2005-Jun 2005 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence (includes letters from Jane Fonda and from Oliver Stone), Jul 2005-Sep 2005 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Oct 2005-Dec 2005 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, [2005] (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Pete Seeger), Jan 2006-Jun 2006 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Jul 2006-Dec 2006 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, [2006] (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Jonathan Kozol and email from Naomi Klein), Jan 2007-Jun 2007 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, Jul 2007-Dec 2007 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, [2007] (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Jan 2008-Jun 2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (includes email from Colin Firth and note and email from Dennis Lehane), Jul 2008-Dec 2008 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, [2008] (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jan 2009-Jun 2009 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Bill Moyers), Jul 2009-Dec 2009 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, [2009] (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (includes letter from Don DeLillo), undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Cuba, 1995-1998 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Prison, 1973-1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Prison, 2000-2009 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Prison, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Abu-Jamal, Mumia (includes related case material), 1989-2003 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Barrett, James W., 1975, 1990-1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Boudin, Kathy, 1983-2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Boudin, Kathy - Includes Related Case Material, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Boudin, Kathy - Includes Series of Articles on Brink's Robbery, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Buck, Marilyn, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Crafts, Charles, 1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Hicks, Kevin D., 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Hicks, Kevin D., 1997-2009, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Irons, Peter, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Lake, Richard Mafundi, 2002-2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Landis, Lois, 2004-2008 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Mann, Eric, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Nassar, George (via Al Amery), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Reilly, Bruce, 2001-2008 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Rufo, Ray, 1974-1977, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Salah-El, Tiyo Attalah, 1986-1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Salah-El, Tiyo Attalah, 2000-2009, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Sousa, Jerry, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Prison - Taylor, Clarence A., 2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn, 1987-2003 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn, 2004-2009, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Canoga Park High School (Thomas Doyle), 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Community College of Vermont, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Georgia State University, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Glendora High School, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Granada Hills / CSUN Magnet High School (Thomas Doyle), 1996, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Hickman High School, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Jefferson Middle School, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Josiah Quincy Upper School, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Memphis Preparatory School, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Ramapo College of New Jersey, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Tigard High School (Bill Patterson), 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Tigard High School (Bill Patterson), 1988-1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - Tualatin High School (Bill Patterson), 1996-2001 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Student Reactions to Zinn - University of Massachusetts, Boston, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Series III: Writings, 1901-2009
  This large series reflects the range of Zinn’s writing, containing actual examples (e.g., articles, essays, book forewords, afterwards, introductions, speeches and pamphlets) as well as much related material including correspondence, contracts, publicity, research notes and reviews. Book and screenplay proposals, album liner notes, letters to the editor, eulogies and special reports are also addressed.
  There is a copy of his doctoral dissertation, “Conscience of the Jazz Age: La Guardia in Congress”, along with a personal hand-written card from Mrs. Marie LaGuardia. Of particular interest is a 767-page typescript of A People’s History of the United States, with corrections, revisions and paste-over insertions in Zinn’s hand. Similar editor’s proof versions of The Politics of History and You Can’t be Neutral on a Moving Train are also included.
  - Articles, Essays, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Articles, Essays, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Articles, Essays, Nov 1963-Dec 1963 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Articles, Essays, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Articles, Essays, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Articles, Essays, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Articles, Essays, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Articles, Essays, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Articles, Essays, 1970-1977 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Articles, Essays, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Articles, Essays, 1990-1999 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Articles, Essays, 2000-2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Articles, Essays, 2004-2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Articles, Essays, 2006-2009 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Articles, Essays (I), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Articles, Essays (II), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Articles, Essays: Boston Globe Op-Eds, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Articles, Essays: Boston Globe Op-Eds, 1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Articles, Essays: College Book Report on The Road to War by Walter Millis, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Articles, Essays: College Essay - "War, In a Glass Case", 1950 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Articles, Essays: Essay Excerpt "Surprises in History", undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Articles, Essays: Essay for Catalogue - "The Times of Arnold Mesches", 1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Articles, Essays: "The First Steps for the Twenty-First Century", undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Articles, Essays: Master of Arts Essay - "The Colorado Fuel and Iron Strike, 1913-1914" (includes subsequent notes and related material), 1952, 2000, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Articles, Essays: "The Politics of History in the Era of the Cold War", [1997] (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Articles, Essays: The Progressive Articles, 1990, 2000-2008, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Articles, Essays: "Rediscovering John Reed" (includes correspondence and notes), 1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Book Afterwords: Marx in Soho: A Play on History by Howard Zinn, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Book Afterwords: What Makes a Man by Rebecca Walker, [2003] (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Book Forewords: The Admirable Radical: Staughton Lynd and Cold War Dissent, 1945-1970 by Carl Mirra, [2009] (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Book Forewords: American Political Prisoners by Stephen M. Kohn, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Book Forewords: Long Shadows: Veterans' Paths to Peace by David Giffey (includes notes and related material), 2005 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Book Forewords: Twilight of Empire by Mike Davis, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Book Forewords: Various, 2007, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Book Introductions: 100 Ways America is Screwing Up the World by John Tirman, [2006] (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Book Introductions: Anarchy of Everyday Life by Ziga Vodovnik, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Book Introductions: Anarchy and Order by Herbert Edwin Read, [1971] (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Book Introductions: The Reform Papers by Henry David Thoreau ( The Higher Law, paperback title), 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Book Introductions: Various, 1971, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Book Prefaces: American Power and the New Mandarins by Noam Chomsky, [2002] (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Book Prefaces: Deserter from Death, [2004] (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Book Proposal: Taking Off from LaGuardia, 1987, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Book Reviews, 1961-1966 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Book Reviews, 1969-1975 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Book Reviews, 1982-1998, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Book Reviews: "A Mess of Death and Documents" (re: Hiroshima) - Includes Related Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Books: Artists in Times of War, 2003-2005 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Books: Declarations of Independence, 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Books: Declarations of Independence - Reviews, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Books: Disobedience and Democracy - Reactions - Correspondence and Related Material (includes letter from Jessica Mitford Treuhaft), 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Books: Disobedience and Democracy - Reviews, 1968-1969 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Books: Failure to Quit, 1991-1999 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Books: The Future of History, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Books: Just War, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Books: Justice in Everyday Life: The Way It Really Works - Reviews, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Books: Justice?: Eyewitness Accounts - Reviews, 1977, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Books: New Deal Thought - Reviews, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Books: On War - Reviews (Indian Edition), 2004 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Books: Original Zinn, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Books: La Otra Historia de los Estados Unidos (Cuban Edition of A People's History of the United States), 1990, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Books: The People Speak, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Books: People's Histories New Press Series (Zinn, Editor), 2000-2007 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Books: People's Histories New Press Series (Zinn, Editor) - A People's Art History of the United States, 2002-2005 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Books: A People's History of American Empire, 2004-2008 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States, 1981, 1993, 1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Audio, 1998-2003 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Editor's Proof (I), [1980] (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Editor's Proof (II), [1980] (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Editor's Proof (III), [1980] (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Editor's Proof (IV), [1980] (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Editor's Proof (V), [1980] (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Fragments, Notes and Resource Material for Chapter "The Coming Revolt of the Guards", 1973-1978, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Proposed Changes / Corrections, 1989-2008, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Reviews, 1979-Apr 1980 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Reviews, May 1980-Aug 1980 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Reviews, Oct 1980-Dec 1980 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Reviews, 1981-1987, 1990-1996 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Reviews, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Reviews - Handlin, Oscar ( The American Scholar, 1981), and Responses (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Reviews - Kazin, Michael ( Dissent, Spring 2004) and Responses, 2004, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Student Project to Design Book Jacket, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - "A Textual-Contextual Analysis of Howard Zinn's A People's History of the United States" (student paper), 1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Twentieth Anniversary Edition, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Various Adaptations ( Echoes: A People's History, a multi-media presentation), 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Various Adaptations (proposed abridgements including a young people's edition), 1991-1994, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Various Adaptations (proposed animation projects), 2005-2008 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Various Adaptations and Formats (proposed website), 1999 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Books: A People's History of the United States - Various Adaptations and Formats (various other proposals), 1995-1999, 2009, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Books: The Politics of History, 1967-1970, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Books: The Politics of History (Second Edition), 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Books: The Politics of History - Editor's Proof (I), [1970] (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Books: The Politics of History - Editor's Proof (II), [1970] (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Books: The Politics of History - Editor's Proof (III), [1970] (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Books: The Politics of History - Editor's Proof (IV), [1970] (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Books: The Politics of History - Reviews, 1970-1975 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Books: Postwar America: 1945-1971, 1966-1975 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Books: Postwar America: 1945-1971 - Reviews, 1973-1974, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Books: Potential Book of Essays on Abolishing War, with Gino Strada (including email from Arundhati Roy), 2005-2006 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Books: Potential Book of Essays on Abolishing War, with Gino Strada (including fax messages and essay from Nadine Gordimer; also email from Cindy Sheehan), 1997-2006, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Books: A Power That Governments Cannot Suppress, 2005-2008 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Books: A Power That Governments Cannot Suppress - Reviews, 2007-2008 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Books: The Power of Nonviolence, [2002] (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Books: The Rule of Law (Zinn was a contributor) - Review, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Books: SNCC: The New Abolitionists, [1964] (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Books: SNCC: The New Abolitionists - Reviews, 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Books: The Southern Mystique, 1958-1964, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Books: The Southern Mystique - Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Books: The Southern Mystique - Reviews, 1964-1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Books: Terrorism and War, 2003-2005 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Books: Three Plays: The Political Theater of Howard Zinn, 2009, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Books: Three Strikes, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Books: The Twentieth Century: A People's History, 1981-1983, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Books: The Twentieth Century: A People's History - Review, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Books: Uncommon Sense, 2007, 2008 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Books: Vietnam: The Logic of Withdrawal, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Books: Vietnam: The Logic of Withdrawal, [1967] (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Books: Vietnam: The Logic of Withdrawal - Reviews, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Books: Vietnam: The Logic of Withdrawal - Reader Actions (includes letters from Edward M. Kennedy and from Edward W. Brooke), 1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Books: Voices of a People's History of the United States, 2004-2005, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Books: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train, 1992-1995, [2002] (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Books: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train - Editor's Proof (I), [1994] (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Books: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train - Editor's Proof (II), [1994] (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Books: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train - Reviews, 1994-1996 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Books: A Young People's History of the United States, 2007, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Books: The Zinn Reader, 1996-2001 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Dissertation: "Conscience of the Jazz Age: LaGuardia in Congress" (personal hand-written card from Mrs. Marie LaGuardia enclosed), 1959, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Drafts and Fragments, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Eulogies: Luria, Salvador (includes correspondence and memorial program), 1991 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1963-2008 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Liner Notes: Fellow Workers (Ani DiFranco), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Films: "Revolution" (unproduced adaptation of A People's History of the United States, script by Howard Fast), 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Films: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train - Correspondence, 2003-2005 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Films: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train - Press, 2003-2004, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Films: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train - Reviews, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Films: You Can't Be Neutral on a Moving Train - Screenings, 2004-2006, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Pamphlets: Columbus, the Indians, & Human Progress 1492-1992 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlets: Hiroshima: Breaking the Silence, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Pamphlets: Power, History & Warfare, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Pamphlets: Times Square, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Plays: As the World Turns - Productions, Jan 2001-Apr 2001, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Plays: As the World Turns - Script (also includes notes and fragments), undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Background, 2001, 2003, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Correspondence, 1985-1986, 2007-2009, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Productions (New York), 1985, undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Productions (White Barn Theater, Westport CT), 1986, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Productions (unknown), undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Reviews, 1986, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Scripts ( Daughter of Venus) (I), 2006 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Scripts ( Daughter of Venus) (II), 2006 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Scripts ( Daughter of Venus) (III), 2006 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Scripts ( Daughter of Venus) (IV), 2006 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Plays: Daughter of Venus / Unsafe Distances - Scripts ( Daughter of Venus), undated (Box 13, Folder 8)